(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-05T18:12:09.738393",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ある日、突如として現れた謎の組織 “holoX”
One day, a mysterious organization suddenly appeared...
構成員5名。与えられたミッションを達成すべく
Secret Society holoX, consisting of five members.
今、立ち上がる！
Now, we rise up!
ちょ〜夢デッカい！デッカい！
Super-duper dream, huge and grand! So huge and grand!
どこまででもデッカいデッカい
No matter where, huge and grand, huge and grand!
さあ行こう！おーいぇー！
Come on, let's go! Hey, hey!
ちょ〜夢デッカい！
Super-duper dream, huge and grand!
本日のアジェンダでござる？
Today's agenda is...
(なにそれ！？)
(What is that?!)
ふぁ〜徹夜明けグロッキーです
I'm groggy from pulling an all-nighter!
(ふっか〜つ！)
(What a drag!)
これじゃ統べる術無いようなもんですな
This is no way to govern anything...
(はぁ〜)
(Hah...)
日本中を駆け回って
Running all over Japan,
このミッション遂行せねばならないらしい
we must accomplish this mission, or so it seems.
ちょっと！？いや、結構不安です
A bit...? No, quite anxious!
それでも我らでやるしかない
Even so, we have no choice but to do it!
皆のものかかれ！
Let's lay claim to everything!
いぇすまいだーく！
Let's get started!
ちょ〜夢デッカい！デッカい！
Super-duper dream, huge and grand! Huge and grand!
手合わせてデッカいデッカい！せーので
Joining hands, huge and grand! Huge and grand! On the count of three—
急転直下！？でも、やるっきゃない！
Sharp plunge?! But we're not backing down!
さあ、今征服宣言！
Now, our declaration of conquest!
こんなにドデッカいデッカい！
So super-duper huge and grand, huge and grand!
希望乗せてデッカいデッカい！
With hope aboard, huge and grand, huge and grand!
さあ行こう！
Come on, let's go!
5人合わせて秘密結社holoX参上！
Five people united, Secret Society holoX has arrived!
(でござる〜)
(For desu~)
てぇてぇはお預けです
Affection is out of the question!
いや、仲の良さは認めるけど
Sure, we admit we get along well,
統べるはエデンの星だから〜！
but ruling is up to the star of Eden!
さあ、作戦会議日和です！
Now, it's strategy meeting time!
(え〜！？)
(Eh?!)
“らしさ”で言えば宇宙一なんですが…
As for our "uniqueness," it's the best in the universe, but...
(まず風呂入って？)
(First, take a bath?!)
日本中のholo xer及び全人類を虜にしたのち
After making holoXers across Japan and all humanity our captives,
息合わせ皆でまだ見ぬ場所までデッカく誘うぜ！
we'll breathe together and invite you to a never-before-seen place, huge and grand!
(山田！)
(Yamada!)
ちょ〜ド級！ゼッタイゼッタイ！
Super-duper top-tier! Absolutely, absolutely!
海も越えゼッタイゼッタイ！せーので
Cross the oceans too, absolutely, absolutely! On the count of three—
荒波でも乗るっきゃないっしょ！
We won't ride even rough waves!
期待の声が聞こえる
Expectant cheers can be heard.
さあ行くぞ！デッカいデッカい！
Come on, let's go! Huge and grand, huge and grand!
不安捨ててデッカいデッカい！
Cast away all worries, huge and grand, huge and grand!
さあ行こう！
Come on, let's go!
ツワモノだって怯まず立ち向かうぜ！
Even as heroes, first we must confront them!
人生簡単にはうまくいかないけど…
Life doesn't always go smoothly, but...
我ら力を合わせればきっと行けるはず！
if we combine our strengths, we'll surely make it!
(いくぞ！)
(Let's go!)
ちょ〜夢デッカい！デッカい！
Super-duper dream, huge and grand! Huge and grand!
手合わせてデッカいデッカい！せーので
Joining hands, huge and grand! Huge and grand! On the count of three—
急転直下！？でも、やるっきゃない！
Sharp plunge?! But we're not backing down!
さあ、今征服宣言！
Now, our declaration of conquest!
こんなにドデッカいデッカい！
So super-duper huge and grand, huge and grand!
希望乗せてデッカいデッカい！
With hope aboard, huge and grand, huge and grand!
さあ行こう！
Come on, let's go!
5人合わせて秘密結社holoX
Five people united, Secret Society holoX...
待っていてねみんなの為参上！
Wait for us, for everyone's sake, we've arrived!
(でござる〜)
(For desu~)
ちょ〜ゆめドデカイ！
Super huge dream!
holoX 3周年、始まるよー！
holoX 3rd anniversary, it's starting!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
というわけで3周年ですね、みなさん！
So, it's the 3rd anniversary, everyone!
3周年ライブのハッシュタグは こちらでございます！
The hashtag for the 3rd anniversary
live is right here!
ポストしてください！
Please post with it!
ということで早速なんですけれども グッズ紹介をしたいと思います！
Without further ado, we'd like
to introduce some goods!
グッズ紹介を今回していただきますみなさんでございます！
You guys will be doing the goods
introduction this time!
一人ずつ自己紹介をお願いします！
Please introduce yourselves one by one!
竜巻せよ！
Spin, tornado!
私の名前は……あっ、すっかり忘れて……
My name is... Ah, completely forgot...
Darknessだ！
Darkness!
一言、ないですか？
Got anything to say?
一言？
Anything?
はい。
Yes.
みんな来てくれてありがとう……。
Thank you everyone for coming...
ありがとう言えましたね。ありがとう言えて偉い。
You said thank you.
Good job saying thank you.
ということで、続いては、こよ！
Next up is Koyo!
みんな、かんかよー！holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！
Everyone, Kankayao!
I'm Hakui Koyori, holoX's brains!
3周年、ここよー！
3rd anniversary, right here!
ばくばくばく生なまー！
Baku baku bakunama!
秘密結社holoXの掃除係、沙花叉クロヱです！
I'm Sakamata Chloe, cleaner of
secret society holoX!
こんばんはでござる！holoXの幼女、じゃなくて用心棒侍の風真いろはでござる！
Good evening! I'm Kazama Iroha,
the bodyguard samurai of holoX!
今年もこれからもかっこいいでござる！
I'll keep being cool this year and beyond!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look favorably upon me!
本日の進行はこの私……！
Today's host is none other than...
鷹嶺ルイが……ノリノリで務めさせていただきます！
Myself, Takane Lui,
and I'll gladly host!
服装何だけどさ、なんでこんなセットなわけ？
What's with these outfits
and this set anyway?
よくお気づきで！やっぱり3周年となると……
Good observation!
When it's the 3rd anniversary...
3Dライブがありまして、あの、歌がメインでございます！
We have a 3D live,
and singing is the main event!
大喜利をしていただきます！
We'll be having an Oogiri session!
最高のholoX周年グッズ、何が入っている？
What's inside the ultimate
holoX anniversary goods?
ピカってかっこいいやつ！
A super flashy and cool item!
てかっこいいやつだったら想像にお任せし
If it's a cool one, I'll leave it to your imagination.
諦めたらしなくちゃいけないの？ いや、許すんだよ
Do I have to give up? No, it's fine.
それは意見の語りだよ
That's just sharing an opinion.
もっと具体的なものでね、もっと具体的なことを考えて 直してきてください。
Think of something more concrete and fix it, please.
あ、早いですね。
Ah, you're fast.
おはようさん。よろしくお願いします。行きますよ。
Good morning. Pleased to work with you. Here we go.
最高のholoX 3周年グッズ何が入ってる？
What's inside the ultimate holoX 3rd anniversary merch?
脱ぎたての靴下
Freshly taken-off socks.
お前だけだろ誰の
You're the only one! Whose are—
いや、靴下は別にいらないけど なんか昔も靴下の話してた気すんだよね
I mean, I don't really need socks... didn't we talk about socks a while ago?
日本酒で別人に
Sake makes you a different person.
いや、靴下は別に、いらないけど、みんな、みんながね... あ、そっかいろはの靴下
I don't really need socks, but everyone... Ah, right, Iroha's socks.
鍵束だったから それでいって
It was a key bundle, so go with that.
お前ら同じこと考えてない
Aren't you guys thinking the same thing?
いや、具体的ことだけ言えるね。
No, only concrete things...
一緒に怪我していこう。 怖いよ。
Let's get hurt together. That's scary!
では、はい。 ランダム要素があるね。
Okay, yes. There's a random element.
ランダム要素、誰のって？ さいねさん、行きますよ。
A random element, whose? Ms. Saine, here we go.
最高のholoX 3周年グッズ何が入ってる？
What's inside the ultimate holoX 3rd anniversary merch?
それはもちろん
That, of course,
我が輩だ！
is yours truly!
え？ 嬉しいでしょ？
Eh? Aren't you happy?
え、何分？ 何分割？ 何分割に入る？
Eh, how many parts? Divided into how many?
分割って？ てっていなの？ 聖遺体塊が1人だけだよ。
Divided? Is it definite? Just one piece of holy relic mass?
この縞模様をね。 いや、角は切れないから。
This striped pattern... No, horns can't be cut.
理事そうってだけだから。 角が切れないなら体は切れるってこと？
It's just for display. If horns can't be cut, does that mean the body can?
いや、そんなこと言ってないよ。 あ、げ足とんだ。
No, I didn't say that! Ah, my leg flew off!
怖い、怖い。1人だけだよ。
Scary, scary. There's only one!
どの、どのよ に？ え、え、とか言うな、お前。
How, how? Don't say 'Eh, eh', you!
お前らだけは欲しいって言うんだ。
You guys are the only ones saying you want it.
ここはいいけど いらないらしい、いらないらしい。
This part is fine, but they don't seem to want it.
ルダール 嬉しいけど、汚いからな そうだな。
Rudar? I'm happy, but it's dirty. True.
あれじゃない？ あの、こよにAIを作ってもらえばいいんじゃない？
Isn't that it? Why don't you have Koyori make an AI?
あ、AIラプラス？ AIラプラス。
Ah, AI Laplace? AI Laplace.
音、高くなるけどね、個あたりは。
Sound gets higher per individual though.
え、そうなの？ あの文章3000分を今から東海以内に読んでいただいて 収録してもらって
Is that so? Read those 3,000 sentences within Tokyo time...
やめとこっか。 やめとこっか。 やめとこっか。
Let's stop. Let's stop. Let's stop.
はい。 はい。 うん。 じゃ、おがりさん行きますか？
Yes. Yes. Yeah. Well, Ms. Ogari, shall we go?
最高のholoX 3周年グッズ何が入ってる？ ギフト券100万円分！
What's inside the ultimate holoX 3rd anniversary merch? 1 million yen in gift certificates!
無理だろ。
No way.
キャッシュバック考えたらね、
If you think about cash back,
でもギフト券なのね？ まあ嬉しい、確かに。でもholoXの3周年グッズだよね？
So it's a gift certificate? Well, I'm happy, sure. But it's holoX 3rd anniversary merch, right?
はい。 あれじゃない？
Yes. Isn't that it?
あのラプだらだけ なんかさっき
Only Lap-dara just a moment ago...
やまだら、やまだら、やまだら、やまだら、やまだら... 山だらじゃねえよ！
Yamadara, Yamadara... That's not Yamadara!
あれちょっと、俺も欲しいみたいな。見た、見た、見た！
Wait, I kinda want it too. I saw it, I saw it!
山田、山田、山田！
Yamada, Yamada, Yamada!
これじゃあまだね、ちょっと、ちょっとグッズ紹介できないな。
With this, we still can't introduce the merch.
え、まだいけないじゃん。 あ、出た！
Eh, we can't go yet? Ah, it came out!
じゃあ、いろはさん、どうぞ。
Then, Iroha-san, please.
じゃあわかった、あったかいやつ！
Then I got it, a warm one!
あったかい、かわいいのよ。
Warm and cute.
室内、からね。ちょっと待ってくださいよ。
Indoor, you see. Please wait a moment.
室内、と、さらにルイさん。ルイ、お願いします。
Indoor, and furthermore Lui-san. Lui, please.
最後にじゃあルイ一、まとめてくださいよ。最後に1個。
Lastly, Lui, summarize it. Just one last thing.
やらない、私はやらない、聞いといて。やれやれ！ホロックスグッズ何が入っている？
I won't do it, I won't do it, listen! Do it! What's inside the holoX merch?
えー、考えてねじゃん。
Uhh, you're not thinking.
ええと、みんなのランダム直筆サイン。
Um, everyone's random handwritten autograph.
本当に欲しいやつ！ 本当に欲しいやつ、本当に欲しいもん。
The one I really want! The one I genuinely want.
確かに全然欲しいけど、何個も買っちゃうよ。
True, I definitely want it, I'd buy so many.
あの、1個は全員分とか。 えー！欲しいよね、みんな。
Like, one is for everyone's worth? Eh! Everyone wants that.
でもさ、リアルなやつ言わない。
But you know, don't say realistic things.
いや、欲しいじゃん、5人分のね。
Well, we want 5 people's worth, right?
1人って言うよりは5人って、あの、特別だよね？
Rather than saying just one, 5 people is special, right?
1個子はわりとチャンスあるから、なんか、伏線だと思われちゃって違いますからね。
If it's just one, there's a fair chance, so people might think it's foreshadowing, but it's different.
違いますから。 あ、ねね、見て、見て、見て！ トレンド。
It's different. Ah, hey, look, look, look! Trending.
トレンド1位になってます！ ありがとう、トレンド1位！ ありがとう！
It's trending #1! Thank you, #1 trend! Thank you!
ありがとうございます。このままお願いします。
Thank you very much. Please keep it that way.
ということで、あの、もう私も限界だし、みんなも限界だし。
With that, I've reached my limit, everyone's reached their limit.
本当だよ。
Seriously.
私が紹介したいと思います。皆さんありがとうございます。それでは、1つ目はこちらでございます。じゃどん！
I'd like to introduce it. Thank you everyone. Well then, the first one is right here. Ta-da!
言って ちゃっ た 。
You said it.
はい。 ラバーマットです！
Yes. A rubber mat!
今需要がね、すごく、はい、高まっております。
Demand is very high right now, yes.
ラバーマット、高値だけにね、あの高まっております。
Rubber mat, because it's high value, it's getting higher.
え、前回に続いてイラストを大きく使用したラバーマットになってます。
Following last time, it's a rubber mat featuring large illustrations.
私たちholoXメンバー5名を、5名の一瞬を切り取ったイラストになっております。イラストはこぶたさんでございます。ありがとうございます！
It features illustrations capturing a fleeting moment of all 5 holoX members. Illustrated by Kobuta-san. Thank you!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いよね。
Super cute, right?
ほしーとかでね、結構ラバーマット欲しいていう人いますから。
People saying 'I want it' - there are quite a few who want rubber mats.
スエットとかにもね。 ね、髪の毛最高にいいよね。
Even on sweats, etc. Right, the hair looks amazing.
素敵なイラストになっているのでぜひ皆さんもしゃ、デスクで使ってください。
It's such a lovely illustration, so please everyone use it at your desk.
はい。ちょっとね、もう時間がないらしいので、私のほうでね、全部紹介したいと思います。
Yes. Well, we're running out of time, so I'd like to introduce everything myself.
え、全部あるの？ 一人だけでいいじゃん。 お前しか映ってないよ、今。
Eh, you have everything? Just one person is fine. Only you are on screen right now.
あ、みんな、みんな紹介したい。
Ah, everyone, everyone wants to introduce.
あ、消して
Ah, delete it—
消して、消しては無い、うん
Delete it— no, not delete it, yeah.
じゃあね、あのみんなで紹介していきましょう。
Well then, let's introduce them together, everyone.
大喜利用のセットはいらないと思いますので、消しちゃいましょう！
I don't think we need the Oogiri set, so let's delete it!
たくさん、たくさん。
Plenty, plenty.
さっき練習したやつ、いきますよ。
Here we go with the one we practiced earlier.
何それ？
What's that?
せーの、パン！
Ready, set, bam!
なんと、なんと？
What, what?
消えたでしょ、これで。
It disappeared, right? With this.
消えてねえ！
It didn't disappear!
ちゃんと。
Properly.
消えてない！
It didn't disappear!
なんか、そういう店みたいになってる。
It looks like some kind of shop now.
違うの！間違ってるぞ！
No! You've got it wrong!
消せ！
Delete it!
味しめてんじゃねえよ、おい。
Don't get greedy, hey.
やめてくださいよ。
Stop that, please.
おい、やめろ。
Hey, stop it.
あ、ちゃんと言え。
Ah, say it properly.
あれ？また消え
Huh? Disappeared again—
あ、消えた。
Ah, it disappeared.
あのセット、マジ何だった？
Seriously, what was that set?
宝
Treasure—
ここからはね、あの茶番もなしで、あのちゃんと説明もね、紹介をしていきたいと思います。
From here on, without any skits, we'd like to
properly explain and introduce them.
お願いしますよ。
Please do.
はい、それでは、こよりさんお願いいたします。
Yes, then Koyori-san, please go ahead.
はい！2つ目のグッズは、こちら！モチーフキーホルダーです！
Yes! The second piece of merchandise is
this: motif keychains!
こちらね、さっきもやっていましたが、2周年記念のときに実装されたもので、例のあれをかたどったキーホルダーとなっております。
As we mentioned earlier, these were implemented
during the 2nd anniversary, shaped after that "certain thing."
例のアレ？例のアレ、なんで作っていただいた。
"That thing"? Why did you make that thing?
シルバーコードの色で再現してありまして、カバンやポーチに使ってさりげなく
Reproduced in silver cord colors, they make
very cute goods you can use on bags or pouches
ホロックスアピールができる、とても可愛いグッズとなっております。
to subtly show off your holoX pride.
カワ、あ、そうかね。ホワイト版なんだね、ホワイト版。
Cute— oh, I see. It's the white version, right? The white version.
あ、そうそう。これルイしか使ってない。
Ah, right, right. Only Lui uses this.
使って、でも1回だけ使う。使ったわ。あれ。KEOのものまねするとき。
She used it— well, she used it once. She did.
When doing a KEO impersonation.
はい、じゃあ、みこや、クロエ！3つ目はリュックです！
Okay, next, Miko, Chloe! The third item is a backpack!
うわあ！すごーい！これは普通に良さそう！
Wow! Amazing! This looks genuinely useful!
はい、丈夫で通勤や通学にも使える、大きな容量のリュックとなっております。
Yes, it's a large-capacity backpack sturdy
enough for commuting to work or school.
サイズや背中部分にもさりげなくXモチーフがちりばめられています。
The X motif is subtly scattered
across the size and back panel.
これ、こよりさんのパソコンとか入れられるんじゃない？
Can't you put Koyori-san's laptop and stuff in this?
そうですね、今日も持ち込んでおります。若いの言ってくれてる。
That's right, I brought it with me today.
The young ones are talking up a storm.
はい！4つ目は、ブロマイドケースです！
Yes! The fourth item is a bromide case!
クセ手書きメッセージ入りの、メッセージをですね、皆さん開いてからのお楽しみと、なっております！
It features duplicated messages from secret society holoX,
which you can look forward to opening up!
イラストはラバーマットと同じ、こぶた先生のものになっておりますんで、
The illustration is by Kobuta-sensei, same as the rubber mat, so—
え、もうすぐ？ギリギリ回収できるんじゃない？中身はぜひね、皆さんお手に届いてから
Wait, very soon? Can you barely collect it?
As for the contents, please look forward to checking them
のお楽しみでね。
once they reach your hands.
さて、新曲の「暁光クロニクル」はみんな聞いていただけたでしょうか？
Now, I wonder if everyone has listened
to the new song "Gyokou Chronicle"?
聞いた！
Heard it!
今日は、聞けるんですか？
Can we hear it today?
え？聞けるんですか？クロエさん。
Eh? Can we hear it, Chloe-san?
え、聞けないパターンってあるんですか？から、聞けないじゃん？
Huh? Is there a pattern where we can't hear it?
Can we not hear it?
もし、もし、もしかしたらね、今日は聞けないかもしれないんですけども、そうだとしても
Well, maybe we can't hear it today,
but even if that's the case,
公式チャンネルのMVや各種ストリーミングサイトで聴くことができます！そして、ボラさんで一括おまとめ購入をしていただくと、
you can listen to it on the official channel's MV and various streaming sites!
Also, if you buy the bundled package on Booth,
ここでしか聴けないキャンペーンボイスもあるとのことですよ！
there are campaign voices you can only hear right here!
さらに、暁光クロニクルのリリース記念ボイスも販売中なので、皆さんぜひ聞いてください、お願いいたします！
Furthermore, the "Gyokou Chronicle" release commemoration
voice is also on sale, so please be sure to listen to it!
お願いします！お願いいたします！
Please! Please do!
そして、今、公式チャンネルのメンバーシップに入ってくれたら
And if you join the official channel membership right now,
我が合いたちの、キービジュアル！さっきのイラストだよ！が使用した限定の絵文字やメンバーからのセリフが使えます！
you can use limited emojis and member quotes
using our key visual—that illustration from earlier!
今！今なうで！今！あ、使ってる、使ってる、使ってみろ！使ってみろ！
Right now! Right now! Right now!
Ah, they're using it, try using it!
ね、holoXの顔をコピーできるから。
You can copy holoX's faces.
コピペ、コピペ！ルイ、ルイ、ルイ、ルイ、ラプ、ラプ、黒、黒、黒！
Copy-paste, copy-paste!
Lui, Lui, Lui, Lui, La+, La+, Kuro, Kuro, Kuro!
こよ、こよ、こよ、こよもできるね。使ってまーす！使ってまーす！
Koyo, Koyo, Koyo, Koyo can do it too.
We're using it! We're using it!
ね、使ってくれてるかな？いいですね。
I wonder if they're using it? That's great.
ということ縁で、3周年ライブは始まったばかりでございます！
With that, the 3rd anniversary live has only just begun!
次は何と！デュエットリレーになっております！初めての！
Next is, what a surprise! A duet relay! For the first time!
だれと？だれと誰？だれと誰？
With whom? With who and who? Who and who?
誰と誰がやる？ルイ、シークレット、シークレット、シークレット恋馬！
Who does it with who? Lui, secret, secret, secret love horse!
ここからはね、ノンストップで盛り上げていきますので、応援よろしくお願いします！
From here on, we'll keep the excitement going nonstop,
so we appreciate your support!
お願いします！
Please!
最初のエキシビションね、もう今匂わせをしていた！
The first exhibition, you were already dropping hints just now!
誰なのか？違うのか？誰、誰、誰、誰、誰、誰！わかる、誰だ、誰だ！いくぞー！
Who is it? Is it wrong? Who, who, who, who, who!
We know, who is it, who is it! Let's go!
やっと見つけた
...I finally found you.
吾輩を探していたのか？
Were you looking for me?
私の、私達の「夢」のために
For my, for our "dream"...
そうか……
Is that so...
ならちょうどいい、吾輩にも力を貸せ
Then that's perfect. Lend me your power too.
この世界を手に入れる
To take this world in our hands.
わかった……力を貸そう
Understood... I will lend you my power.
手をだしてくれ
Give me your hand.
ええ
Yes.
これで我が輩たちは共犯者だ
With this, we are accomplices.
きっと手を繋ぐだけでゾッとされる
I'm sure we freak them out just by holding hands
ラットレース抜け出したら疎まれるよ
You're reported when you opt out of the rat race
突如変異じゃない ただの僕さ
It's not a mutation; it's just the way I am
XとかYとか
Whether that's X or Y
べき論者様は善悪多頭飼い
Stubborn people hoard many goods and evils
僕が君を“侵害”するって言いふらしている
They're spreading the word that I've "infringed" upon you
Oh...
Mr. Crazy
Villain Villain 夜行性の花弁
Villain Villain, nocturnal petals
違う服装で君の前では 男子のフリをする
I wear different clothes and pretend to be a boy in front of you
拝啓 Dr. Durand-Durand 迎いにきてください
Dear Dr. Durand-Durand, please come pick me up
顔も知らない誰かにとって 僕はもうヴィラ-ン
Even to those I don't know, I'm already deemed a villain
蛇蝎ライフ
My hated life
挙句の果ての搦め手
In the end becomes inflamed
逸脱の性をまたひた隠す
Keeping the deviant sex secret
雄蕊と雄蕊じゃ立ち行かないの?
A dead end with stamens and stamens?
ねぇ知ってんのかな
Hey, do you know
乱歩という作家のことを
a writer named Rampo?
Import you 造花も果ては実を結ぶ
Import you, artificial flowers will bear fruit
ぶれっちんじゃねーよ 多多様性の性
Do not be afraid, a wide variety of genders
愛しい悲しい話をしようか ゼラチン質の「で?」
Let's talk loving and sad. So what?
Mr. Crazy
Villain Villain 可能性に幸あれ 僕のハート1LDK
Villain Villain, be happy with possibilities, my heart is 1LDK
嫉妬くらいはさせてよ Hi there! モットーYOLO
Let me be jealous. Hi there! My motto is YOLO
微熱愛でいいのに 誰も知らない 知られたくない 皮膚の下
Need a little love. Nobody knows, I don't want anyone to know under my skin
素晴らしき悪党どもに捧げる唄
A song dedicated to the great villains
骨まで演じ切ってやれ悪辣に
Completely playing the villain
残酷な町ほど綺麗な虹が立つ
A cruel town has a beautiful rainbow
猥雑広告に踊るポップ体の愛
Dancing on obscene ads, pop fonts love
Oh...
Mr. Crazy
Villain Villain 夜行性の花弁
Villain Villain, nocturnal petals
違う服装で君の前では 男子のフリを!
I wear different clothes and pretend to be a boy in front of you!
拝啓 Dr. Durand-Durand ここだよ
Dear Dr. Durand-Durand, I'm here!
顔も知らない誰かにとって 僕はもうヴィラ-ン
Even to those I don't know, I'm already deemed a villain
蛇蝎ライフ
My hated life
挙句の果ての……
In the end...
Villain Villain 夜行性の花弁
Villain Villain, nocturnal petals
違う服装で君の前では 男子のフリを
I wear different clothes and pretend to be a boy in front of you
拝啓 Dr. Durand-Durand 迎いにきてください
Dear Dr. Durand-Durand, please come pick me up
顔も知らない誰かにとって 僕はもうヴィラ-ン
Even to those I don't know, I'm already deemed a villain
蛇蝎ライフ
My hated life
挙句の果ての 挙げ句の果ての 挙げ句の果てノ
In the end, in the end, in the end
Villain
やぁ、「博衣こより」、研究に精が出るね
Hey, "Hakui Koyori", working hard on your research, I see.
またあなたですか……
You again...
君が自由にできる環境は用意できたよ。それに、面白いリーダーもね
I've prepared an environment where you can do as you please. And an interesting leader, too.
ん……
Hmm...
それに、見たくない？自分の“研究”が世界中に広がっていく姿を
And wouldn't you like to see it? Your "research" spreading all across the world?
ん……
Hmm...
私は興味あるけどなぁ
I'm certainly interested, though.
なるほど……そこまで言うなら付き合ってあげましょう。
I see... If you say so much, I'll go along with it.
大丈夫ですか？ぼくは劇薬かもしれませんよ……？
Are you sure? I might be a potent poison...
ははっ、毒を喰らわばってね
Ha, in for a penny, in for a pound...
ああ足らないものはなんだ 僕らの人生
What is it that's not good enough about our lives?
正解どこなんだ 探せよ探せ
Where's the right answer? Look for it, look for it!
ああ例外ない 二進も三進も
There are no exceptions in any way,
零下以内なら 劣化以外ないな
if it's below zero or mere deterioration.
ああ正味クソゲーだ カラ回り回れ
Ah, what a piece of junk, spin, spin our wheels.
(Oh)
ああ倦怠モード苦だ 僕らの人生
In exhaustion mode, our lives are "suffering"!
校内猛毒だ 屈めよ屈め
It's a deadly poison, give in to it, give in to it!
ああ盛大KNIGHT 和気あいあいゴッコは
A magnificent knight when pretending to be happy,
成敗 DIE by 生産性ないな
win or lose, you die by a lack of productivity.
ああ後悔もう独だ 笑えよ笑え
Regrets are already "lonely"—smile, smile!
(wow wow)
心のレシピは かまちょ味 寂ジャンキー
The recipe for my heart is attention-seeking and a nirvana junkie.
だんだん強がって ドロドロに付す
I pretend more and more to be strong and end up face-down in the mud.
ドクドク呑み込んで 苦しんで泣いて吐き出せないの
Gulping down the poison, feeling pain, crying, there's no coughing it up—
ベノ・ベノ・ベノム
veno-veno-venom,
さよなら
goodbye!
あらま 求愛性 孤独毒 流るる
Ah, flirtiness, loneliness, poison flowing continuously.
(愛をもっと)戴冠な。ねえ 痛い痛いの飛んでけ
(Give me more love.) Make the pain go away!
存在感 血 ドクドク こぼるる
Presence, isn't the blood gushing out and spilling continuously?
(ないの？もっと) 愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
(Isn't there? More!) More love, love, sorrow, sorrow—
叫べ ベノ・ベノム、目！
shout out, venom, no!
最高点 ゼロだ 僕らの人生
The highest we've scored in our lives is zero.
ダンゼンテンションローだ 屈めよ屈め
We're completely low-energy—give in to it, give in to it!
ロンリーナイト 鉄平回って
On a lonely night the clock strikes midnight,
労無い無い脳内HOPEもう一回
and in my unclouded brain there's hope once again.
オーバードーズ系だ AgareよAgare
The penalty is to overdose—get up, get up!
心の中々は ムリオブムリジャンキー
My heart is full of helplessness; I'm a helplessness junkie.
どんどん強がって バラバラに付す
I pretend more and more to be strong and end up in pieces.
ドクドク呑み込んで 苦しんで泣いて逃げ出せないの
Gulping down the poison, feeling pain, crying, there's no running away—
ベノ・ベノ・ベノム
veno-veno-venom.
あらま 求愛性 孤独毒 流るる
Ah, flirtiness, loneliness, poison flowing continuously.
(愛をもっと)戴冠な。ねえ 痛い痛いの飛んでけ
(Give me more love.) Make the pain go away!
存在感 既読 ドクドク 欲しがる
Presence, "message read," don't you want some poison?
(ないの？もっと) 愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
(Isn't there? More!) More love, love, love, love—
砕け ベノ・ベノム
destroy it, venom, no!
もう悪性 独々 巡るる
The poison and evil have already found their mark,
(愛でもっと)生害な。ねえ 痛い痛いのシクシク
spinning continuously, I've been wounded more by sorrow.
存在抹殺 毒々 消ゆるる
Hey, it hurts, it hurts, I'm sick, sick,
(ないのずっと) 愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)
a poison to erase my existence—doesn't it always keep disappearing?
求愛性 孤独毒 流るる
Love, love, sorrow, sorrow...
(愛をもっと)戴冠な。ねえ 痛い痛いの飛んでけ
Flirtiness, loneliness, poison flowing continuously.
存在感 血 ドクドク こぼるる
(Give me more love.) Make the pain go away!
(ないの？もっと) 愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
Presence, isn't the blood gushing out and spilling continuously?
叫べ ベノ・ベノム
(More love!) More love, love, sorrow, sorrow—
shout out, venom, shout out, venom,
叫べ ベノ・ベノム！(目！)
shout out, venom, no!
あらま 求愛性 孤独毒 流るる
Ah, flirtiness, loneliness, poison flowing continuously.
(愛をもっと)戴冠な。ねえ 痛い痛いの飛んでけ
(Give me more love.) Make the pain go away!
存在感 既読 ドクドク 欲しがる
Presence, "message read," don't you want some poison?
(ないの？もっと) 愛(愛)愛！(愛！)
(Isn't there? More!) More love, love, love, love—
砕け ベノ・ベノム
destroy it, venom, no!
もう悪性 独々 巡るる
The poison and evil have already found their mark,
(愛でもっと)生害な。ねえ 痛い痛いのシクシク
spinning continuously, I've been wounded more by sorrow.
存在抹殺 毒々 消ゆるる
Hey, it hurts, it hurts, I'm sick, sick,
(ないのずっと) 愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)愛！(愛！)
a poison to erase my existence—doesn't it always keep disappearing?
求愛性 孤独毒 流るる
Love, love, sorrow, sorrow...
(愛をもっと)戴冠な。ねえ 痛い痛いの飛んでけ
Flirtiness, loneliness, poison flowing continuously.
存在感 血 ドクドク こぼるる
(Give me more love.) Make the pain go away!
博衣こより
ふふふふふふふふ 楽しいなぁ！
[Title: Hakui Koyori] Fun, fun, fun, fun, so fun!
沙花叉クロヱ
ちょ、ちょっと！それ何してるの！？
[Title: Sakamata Chloe] Wait, wait! What are you doing?
博衣こより
えっ？何って……実験？
[Title: Hakui Koyori] What? ...An experiment?
沙花叉クロヱ
それぜっっっっっったい、だめだよ！なんかめちゃくちゃ嫌な濁り方してって！
[Title: Sakamata Chloe] That's—no way! Why is it such a nasty, murky color?!
博衣こより
え？それがいいんじゃん
[Title: Hakui Koyori] Eh? Isn't that fine?
沙花叉クロヱ
やめようよ！それ掃除するの沙花叉の仕事になるんだからぁ！！
[Title: Sakamata Chloe] Stop it! Cleaning that up will be Sakamata's job, you know!!
博衣こより
ふふふふ……知ってる？
[Title: Hakui Koyori] Fu-fu-fu... Did you know?
博衣こより
奇跡も！魔法も！あるらしいよ！
[Title: Hakui Koyori] Miracles and magic are real too!
沙花叉クロヱ
もうすでに おかしくなってんじゃん！もーーーーーっ！
[Title: Sakamata Chloe] You've already gone crazy! Stop it—!
伝え合った心の温度を そっと大事そうに抱え歩いていた
We softly held the warmth of our hearts,
答えのない願いの中で 言葉は未来変えて
changing the future with our words.
幼い頃ずっと夢見ていた私にはまだ遠いけど
The things I dreamed of when I was young are still far away,
君がいれば少しは強くなれる気がして 明日の足を塗り重ねた
but when you're here, I feel like I'm a little stronger,
明日の色を重ね塗った
as the colors of tomorrow paint over each other.
呼んだ希望辿って止めた世界を超えた
The hope summoned pursued us and surpassed the world,
諦めない想いいつしか心結べた
and the feeling to never give up connected our hearts before we knew it.
泣いていたって笑って明日迎えに行こう
Instead of crying, let's smile and head for tomorrow.
誰が止めても一切聞く気がない
No matter who tries to stop me, I won't listen.
夢を見るも掴むも自分次第
Whether I dream or grasp it is up to me.
宙に舞い野原を駆け る自由自在
Dancing in the air, running freely across fields,
こんなイケてるチームなんざ他にない
There's no other cool team like this.
you know?
1, 2, 3 止め処なく
1, 2, 3, endlessly,
gain, again, again let’s snatch away
gain, again, again let's snatch away
どきな どきな 三本柱のお通りだ
Step aside, make way, the big three are passing through!
真っ赤な顔してどうした?
Got a red face, what's wrong?
まだやり合うなんて正気かい?
You think we're still even? Are you sane?
とうに取って仕切った
Long since settled,
いかにも 俺がここのリーダー
I'm clearly the leader here.
okay, 止めれるもん なら止めてみな
Okay, if you can stop us, try it.
oh yeah! かかってこい
Oh yeah! Bring it on!
逃げも隠れもしないぜ boy
No running, no hiding, boy.
圧倒的ってのはこういうもん
Overwhelming power is like this.
go crazy
空より高く飛べ 簡単でしょ?
Fly higher than the sky, easy right?
尻尾巻くくらいなら下がってろ
If you're tailing behind, back off.
最高が何か証明しよう
Let's prove what's best.
go crazy
そう固まんないなルーキー
Don't huddle up like rookies,
そう急かしないさグループー
Don't rush so much, groupies.
おかげさまで暖まった空気
Thanks to you, the air warmed up,
だがこの先ちょっとばか注意
Though a bit cautious from here on.
thrill like a movie they're shooting??
ご自由に
Do as you like.
でも言っていんだろこっちも少しも手は抜かないのが流儀
Even so, we won't slack off a bit, as expected.
1, 2, 3 止め処なく
1, 2, 3, endlessly,
gain, again, again let’s snatch away
gain, again, again let's snatch away
どこだってフィールドさ 切って貼ってスクラップ & ビルド
Wherever we go is the field, cutting, pasting, scrap & build.
勝利の女神からのキスを受けたお前にとってのビースト
To you who received a kiss from the goddess of victory, the ultimate beast.
幾度も幾度も傷を負ってなおこのスピードフロー
Taking hits time and time again, yet keeping this speed flow.
止めれるもん なら止めてみな
If you can stop us, try it.
oh yeah! かかってこい
Oh yeah! Bring it on!
逃げも隠れもしないぜ boy
No running, no hiding, boy.
圧倒的ってのはこういうもん
Overwhelming power is like this.
go crazy
空より高く飛べ 簡単でしょ?
Fly higher than the sky, easy right?
尻尾巻くくらいなら下がってろ
If you're tailing behind, back off.
最高が何か証明しよう
Let's prove what's best.
go crazy
all we do is win
so all my people say
all we do is win まだ遊び足りないぜ
All we do is win, still can't get enough play.
all we do is win やってやる何回だって
All we do is win, we'll do it as many times as it takes.
ハンデ も何でもかんでもであっても関係もないほど
No matter the handicap, whatever, it doesn't even matter.
圧倒的 show time
Overwhelming showtime.
意地と覚悟夢に掛ける担保
Will and determination staked as collateral on a dream.
今日も明日も一度引けばラスト
Today and tomorrow, once drawn, it's the last.
どこからどこまでリアルかすら
How real is it, from where to where?
グラグラ揺らぐ落差 = 苦楽の間
Wobbling disparity = the interval of agony.
益々増す戦略が塞ぐ 「自由」を歌うのさ
Strategies piling up more and more, let's sing of "freedom"!
oh yeah! かかってこい
Oh yeah! Bring it on!
逃げも隠れもしないぜ boy
No running, no hiding, boy.
圧倒的ってのはこういうもん
Overwhelming power is like this.
go crazy
空より高く飛べ 簡単でしょ?
Fly higher than the sky, easy right?
尻尾巻くくらいなら下がってろ
If you're tailing behind, back off.
最高が何か証明しよう
Let's prove what's best.
go crazy
everybody この世界を遊べ
Everybody, play this world.
すくい信じて割れた
Who could have believed?
想い 私が始まりにだって
The feelings I started with back then,
君の笑顔を取り戻すよ
Will bring your smile back to you.
真実の奇跡になって
Becoming a miracle of truth,
手をつなごう
We'll make it.
そばにいよお
Stay by my side.
風真いろは なかなかのやるでござるな！
Well done, Kazama Iroha!
そっちこそ！
Same to you!
いやあ、戦闘員がいると楽だねぇ。
Man, having combatants makes things easy.
ん？クロヱ殿、サボってるのでござるか？
Hm? Chloe-dono, are you slacking off?
サボってないよ、ほら戦ってる戦ってる！
Not slacking! Look, I'm fighting, fighting!
……そうなのでござるか？であれば、どんどん行くでござるよ！
Is that so? Then let's keep moving forward!
わあーい らーくちーん！めっちゃハッピー！
Yay, Raku-chian! So happy!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
Playing a melody that reaches deep into your heart,
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer
作詞・作曲：BETTI
Music and lyrics: BETTI
儚く散った淡い片想い
That fleeting, pale unrequited love,
笑い話だね 今となれば
It's a laughing matter now.
見る物全て 輝いて見えた
All those days when everything I saw shone bright,
あの日々がキレイに笑ってるよ
Are smiling at me clearly.
我慢する事だけ 覚えなきゃいけないの?
Do I have to remember how to hold back?
「大人になって頂戴ね?」ならなくていいよ
"Act like an adult," you say? Not a chance.
知らない事ばかり 知らないなんて言えなくて
I can't just say I know nothing when I don't,
「大変お似合いで」ウソついてゴメんね
And saying "It suits you well" was just a lie, sorry!
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
Playing a melody that reaches deep into your heart.
つまらない「たてまえ」や やな事全部 消してあげるから
I'll wipe away all your boring pretenses and troubles
この音で
with this sound!
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
With no special talents, the one and only thing
少しだけだけど 出来る事
that I can do, even if just a little...
心躍らせる 飾らない 言葉
Heart-throbbing, unadorned words
電子音で伝えるよ
I will convey through electronic sounds.
好きになる事 理屈なんじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic,
「こじつけ」なんて いらないんじゃない?
You don't need any far-fetched excuses, right?
時代のせいと 諦めたらそこまで
If you give up blaming the times, that's as far as you'll go
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
Nothing starts unless you take a step forward.
「ゴメンね夜遅く 寝るところだったでしょ?」
"Sorry for calling so late, were you going to bed?"
「驚いた 私もかけようとしてた」
"I'm surprised, I was just about to call you too."
心の裏側をくすぐられているような
Like having the back of our hearts tickled,
惹かれ合う2人に 幸せな音を
sending a happy sound to us two drawn together!
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy synthesizer, see? It gets fun!
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Playing a melody to wipe away tears.
強がりなんだっていいんじゃない? 別に
Is it okay to put up a front? Whatever, right?
自分に素直になれればいい
As long as you can be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
With no special talents, the one and only thing
少しだけだけど 出来る事
that I can do, even if just a little...
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
Simple feelings that make you a bit shy,
電子音で伝えるよ
I will convey through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の 胸の奥まで
Happy synthesizer, deep into your chest
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
つまらない「たてまえ」や やな事全部
I'll wipe away all your boring pretenses and troubles
消してあげるから この音で
with this sound!
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
With no special talents, the one and only thing
少しだけだけど 出来る事
that I can do, even if just a little...
心躍らせる 飾らない 言葉
Heart-throbbing, unadorned words
電子音で伝えるよ
I will convey through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね 楽しくなるよ
Happy synthesizer, see? It gets fun!
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
Playing a melody to wipe away tears.
強がりなんだっていいんじゃない? 別に
Is it okay to put up a front? Whatever, right?
自分に素直になれればいい
As long as you can be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄も無い 僕に唯一つ
With no special talents, the one and only thing
少しだけだけど 出来る事
that I can do, even if just a little...
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち
Simple feelings that make you a bit shy,
電子音で伝えるよ
I will convey through electronic sounds.
いろはーーーっ！スイッチ！
Iroha—! Switch!
え、ラプ殿？
Eh, Lady Laplus?
助けに来たぞ！すけだちってやつだ！
I've come to save you! It's reinforcement!
助かるでござる！
Much appreciated!
でも、よく場所がわかったでござるな？
But how did you know where I was?
ふん！吾輩は総帥だぞ！
Hmph! I am the Commander!
そんなことより、ほら行くぞいろは！
More importantly, let's go, Iroha!
おう、でござるっ！
Right, let's go!
そっと吐き出すため息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sigh I let out
後悔は苦い味残して いつもなんで? 肝なこと言えないまま
Regrets left a bitter taste. Why can I never say what matters?
次の朝日が顔を出している 嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
The next morning sun shows its face. I slice up my hateful fate with a knife.
もう一度やり直したら キミに出会えないかも
If I started over once more, maybe I wouldn't have met you.
ぼくの声が響いた瞬間に始まる 命のリミット
The moment my voice echoed, life's limit begins.
心臓がカウントしてる 叶えても叶えても終わらない願い
My heart is counting. A wish that never ends no matter how many times granted.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は いつか止まった僕を置いていく
Running in a sweat, the world's second hand leaves behind me who stopped.
あと何回キミと笑えるの? 試してるんだ僕を Catch the Moment
How many more times can I smile with you? It's testing me, Catch the Moment.
一個幸せを数えるたびに 変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
Every time I count a piece of happiness, I get scared of the changing future,
愛情の種を大切に育てよう 分厚い雲も やがて突き破るかな
but let's nurture the seed of love. Will it pierce through thick clouds?
キミの声が響いた 僕の全身を通って 心臓のドアをノックしている
Your voice echoed through my entire body, knocking on my heart's door.
「怯え」でも開けいしちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
Even if it's "cowardice", I'll open it because I want to believe.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は いつか止まった僕を置いていく
Running in a sweat, the world's second hand leaves behind me who stopped.
あと何回キミと笑えるの? 試してるんだ僕を Catch the Moment
How many more times can I smile with you? It's testing me, Catch the Moment.
逃さないよ僕は この瞬間を掴め Catch the Moment
I won't let you go, I'll grasp this moment, Catch the Moment!
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
Quietly, I inhaled the sigh I let out
後悔は苦い味残して
Regret leaves a bitter taste behind
いつも なんで? 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it that I can never say what matters?
次の朝日が顔を出してる
The next morning's sun is showing its face
嫌になった運命を ナイフで切り刻んで
Slicing up the hateful fate with a knife
もう一度やり直したら キミに出逢えないかも
If I started over, maybe I couldn't meet you
僕の声が響いた 瞬間に始まる
It all starts the moment my voice resounds
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしている
Life's limit, my heart is counting down
叶えても叶えても 終わらない願い
Wishes that never end, no matter how many come true
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
The seconds hand of the world I ran through
いつか 止まった僕を置いていく
Leaves behind the me who stopped
あと何回キミと笑えるの?
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してんだ僕を Catch the Moment
Testing myself, Catch the Moment
一個幸せを数えるたびに 変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
Every time I count a piece of happiness, I get scared of the changing future
愛情の種を 大切に育てよう
Let's nurture the seed of love with care
分厚い雲も やがて突き破るかな
Will it eventually break through the thick clouds?
キミの声が響いた 僕の全身を通して
Your voice resounded, passing through my whole body
心臓のドアを ノックしている
Knocking on the door of my heart
「怯え」でも開けちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
Even with "cowardice", I'll open it because I want to believe
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に
Right at my feet, where I thought there was nothing
いつか 深く 確かな根を生やす
Someday, deep, certain roots will grow
嵐の夜が来たとしても 揺らいだりはしない
Even if a stormy night comes, I won't waver
何度でも
No matter how many times
追いかけたり追い越したり キミがふいに分かんなくなって
Chasing and overtaking, and you suddenly become hard to understand
息をしたタイミングが 合うだけで嬉しくなったりして
Just syncing our breaths makes me happy
集めた一秒を 永久にして行けるかな
Can I make every gathered second eternal?
僕の声が響いた 瞬間に始まる
It all starts the moment my voice resounds
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしている
Life's limit, my heart is counting down
ボクの声が響いた ときに始まる
My voice resounded when it started
命のリミット
Life's limit,
心臓がカウントして叶えても叶えても終わらない願い
my heart is counting, wishes that never end no matter how many come true
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針は
The seconds hand of the world I ran through
いつか止まった 僕を置いていく
Leaves behind the me who stopped
あと何回キミと笑えるの?
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してんだ僕を Catch the Moment
Testing myself, Catch the Moment
一個幸せを数えるたびに 変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
Every time I count a piece of happiness, I get scared of the changing future
愛情の種を 大切に育てよう
Let's nurture the seed of love with care
分厚い雲も やがて突き破るかな
Will it eventually break through the thick clouds?
キミの声が響いた 僕の全身を通して
Your voice resounded, passing through my whole body
心臓のドアを ノックしている
Knocking on the door of my heart
「怯え」でも開けちゃうんだよ 信じたいから
Even with "cowardice", I'll open it because I want to believe
Catch the Moment
と、まぁ、こんな感じで全員揃いました……と
And, well, everyone is gathered like this...
こんな感じって、どんな感じですか……総帥？
What do you mean by "like this", Souei?
まぁ、こんな感じってことは、こんな感じだよねぇ、ラプちゃん？
Well, "like this" means just like this, right, Lap-chan?
相変わらず、適当言ってんなぁ……
Still talking nonsense as usual...
まあまあ、それもholoXっぽいでござるよ
Well, well, that's very holoX-like too.
うるさい！holoXの戦いはここからなんですー！お前ら準備はいいか！！
Shut up! holoX's battle starts right here! Are you guys ready?!
次の曲は！ チルドレンレコード！！！
The next song is! Children Record!!!
白いイヤホンを耳に当て 少しニヤッとして合図する
Putting white earphones in my ears, I give a little grin and signal
染み込んだこの温度が ドアをノックした瞬間に溢れそうになるよ
This seeped-in temperature is about to overflow the moment it knocks on the door
「まだ視えない?」目を凝らし臨む争奪戦
"Still can't see it?" Squinting at the scramble
あの日途絶えちゃった脳裏から 「今だ、取り戻せ」とコードが鳴り出しそう
From the brain where it was cut off that day, the code is about to ring out "Now, take it back"
愛しくて、辛くて、世界を嫌ったヒトの酷く理不尽な「構成」
The terribly unreasonable "composition" of someone who loved, suffered, and hated the world
肯定してちゃ未来は生み出せない
If we keep affirming it, we can't create the future
白いイヤホンを耳にあて
Putting white earphones to my ears,
少しニヤッとして合図する
I give a slight smirk and signal.
染め込んだこの温度がドアをノックした瞬間に
The warmth I absorbed, the moment it knocks on the door,
溢れそうになるよ
is about to overflow.
「まだ見えない?」
"Can you still not see it?"
目を凝らして臨む 争奪戦
Straining my eyes for the battle of attrition.
あの日 齷齪した脳裏から
From the flustered back of my mind that day,
「今だ、取り戻せ」とコードが鳴り出しそう
the code seems to ring out, "Now, take it back!"
愛しすぎて、辛すぎて、
Loving too much, hurting too much,
世界を嫌ったヒトの
of the person who hated the world,
酷く理不尽な「構成」
a horribly unreasonable "composition."
肯定してちゃ未来は生み出せない
You can't create a future by just accepting it.
少年少女前を向く
Boys and girls, look forward,
暮れる炎天下さえ希望論だって
even the setting scorching sun is optimism.
「ツレモドセ」
"Take it back!"
三日月が赤く燃え上がる
The crescent moon burns red.
さあさあ、コードを0で刻ませ
Come on, carve the code at zero,
想像力の外側の世界へ
to a world outside the bounds of imagination.
オーバーな空想戦線へ
To the over-the-top fantasy battlefront,
「お先にどうぞ」って舌を出す
sticking out my tongue, saying "After you."
余裕ぶった無邪気な目
With innocent, feigned-composure eyes.
「ほら出番だ」パスワードで目を覚ましたじゃじゃ馬は 止まらない
The untamed horse awakened by the password "Look, it's your turn" won't stop.
もう夜が深くなる
Night is deepening further.
「オコサマ」なら燃える 延長戦
If we're "brats," the overtime battle burns brighter.
逆境ぐあいがクールだろ?
The level of adversity is cool, right?
寝れないね、まだまだ。
Can't sleep yet, not yet.
ほら早く!早く!!
Come on, faster! Faster!!
インテンポで視線を合わせて
Matching our gazes in in-tempo,
ハイタッチでビートが鳴り出せば
if the beat rings out with a high-five.
考えてちゃ遅いでしょう?
Thinking about it would be too late, wouldn't it?
ワンコードで視線を合わせて
Matching our gazes with one chord,
ぶっ飛んだグルーヴが渦巻けば
if a blown-away groove swirls around,
冗談じゃないみえるはず
no joke, it should be visible.
そのハイエンドの景色の隙間に
In the gaps of that high-end scenery,
さあ どうだいこの暑さも
now, how is this heat too?
すれ違いそうだった価値観も
And the values that seemed like they'd pass each other by,
悪くないかな 目を開き
not bad, right? Opening my eyes,
手を取り合ったら
when we joined hands.
意外とチープな言葉も合言葉だって言い合える
Even surprisingly cheap words can be called our passwords.
少しだけ 前を向ける
Able to look forward just a little bit.
少年少女
Boys and girls,
前を向く
look forward,
揺れる炎天下すら希望論だって
even the swaying scorching sun is optimism.
思い出し 口に出す
Remembering it and speaking it out.
人生で一日しかない今日を愛そう
Let's love today, which only happens once in a lifetime.
昨日はリセット
Yesterday is reset.
僕達は春を青く青く塗り替える
We repaint spring bluer and bluer.
青春に無縁な一人ぼっち普通の僕
Just an ordinary me, clueless about youth.
誰もがそう思ってた特別なのに
Even though everyone thought they were special.
毎日に見飽きてるの?
Are you getting tired of every day?
意思を持って生きているの?
Are you living with intention?
みんな違うけれど愛は持って生きているよ
Everyone is different, but we live with love.
人生で一日しかない今日を愛そう
Let's love today, which only happens once in a lifetime.
昨日はリセット
Yesterday is reset.
僕達は春を青く青く塗り替える
We repaint spring bluer and bluer.
もうきみの心 チクッとしちまえ わおーん！
Make your heart go prick, woof!
「絶対無理」思ったし
I thought "That's totally impossible"
だってだって不安になるし
Because, because I get anxious.
全然嘘つけないし
I can't lie at all.
だってだってバカ真っ直ぐだし
Because, because I'm dead honest.
目指すキラキラもきみ次第だ
The sparkle we aim for depends entirely on you.
1, 1, ステップアップ
1, 1, Step up.
ちょっとずつ進めば夢の式解けちゃうの
If we advance little by little, the formula of dreams will be solved.
なりたいぼくを きみが好きなぼくを
The "me" I want to be, the "me" you love.
ちゃん 余りなく 魅せたいの
I want to show you fully without surplus.
あっちゅっちゅ びっくりするほどできない じゃん
Accyuicchu, I can't do it as much as I'm surprised, right?
間違って悩んだり ばっか じゃん
Making mistakes and worrying, totally right?
だけどきみに見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me.
ぼくはきみを迎えに行くんだ 出会えた ならハッピー
I'm going to welcome you, if we could meet, then it's happy.
わおー わおー だ叫んじゃえ
Woof, woof, go on and shout!
風がそっと吹いたら
When the wind gently blows,
始まる合図でござる！
it's the signal for it to begin!
ah このハードモードな日々も
ah, even these hard-mode days,
days 歩き出すことためらうけれど
days, though I hesitate to start walking.
bgm 決めてさあ、人生 エンジョイ勢でのんびりゆこう
Deciding on the BGM, come on, let's go leisurely as enjoyers of life.
先の見えない乱世
A turbulent era where the future can't be seen.
自分の道通りゃんせ
Walk your own path as you please.
オーケー 生きてりゃきっと何とかなるさ
Okay, if you're alive, surely something will work out.
だいじょうぶだいじょうぶ！
It's okay, it's okay!
後？前？方向なんてわからない
Back? Front? I don't know the direction.
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
Even a daily life entering such a labyrinth,
一歩歩き出せたら それが前になるのか
if I can take a step forward, will that become the front?
万事快調気味な朝でも
Even on a morning that feels all-around smooth,
頭鬱滞気味な夜でも
even on a night with a sluggish mind.
笑ってるけどどこか泣いてん'nだ
I'm smiling, but somewhere I'm crying.
痛み味ご賞美の避難
A refuge of tasting pain as a reward.
思ってるけどずっとためてん'nだ
I'm thinking it, but I've been bottling it up all along.
密の味呪いの哀願
The taste of nectar, the supplication of a curse.
すりへってにごってアイラブジブン
Worn out, clouded, I love myself.
いつだってそうやってこもってふかんしょう
Always holoping myself away and staying indifferent like that.
起きれなくてキスをしてみるけど
I can't wake up, so I try giving a kiss, but
乾いたかさぶた痛くなってん'nだ
the dried scab is starting to hurt.
わがままに選んでわぽいてんして
Choosing selfishly and pointing...
わからない言葉が
Words I don't understand,
鳴り止まない電話が
the endless ringing phone,
埋められない温度差 とまどう日日
the unbridgeable temperature gap, bewildered days.
1人きり残された
Left all alone,
無機質な時間には
in this inorganic time,
こなせない問題 どうするの?
an unmanageable problem, what should I do?
争いが増えていく
Conflicts keep increasing,
明日が見えなくて
and I can't see tomorrow.
大事なモノさえ なくしかけて
Even losing what's precious to me,
本音が消えていく
my true feelings fade away.
君だけに教えてもいいか
Shall I share it with just you?
メッキなし バッドハーフ
No plating, bad half,
君は君 いらぬ気遣い
you are just you, needless worry.
不毛なボード ジナスノス ノルコトデハイ アッパッパ
A barren board, jumping on board, uppappa!
我が道を行く Minority
Walking my own path as a minority,
艶っぽくあやに
seductively and subtly,
しんなり魅せる Pure なハート
charmingly showing a pure heart.
のっさごめえ
Tossed away,
夢描いちゃって
dreaming away,
我が道を行く Minority
Walking my own path as a minority,
艶っぽくあやに
seductively and subtly,
しんなり魅せる Pure なハート
charmingly showing a pure heart.
のっさごめえ
Tossed away,
夢描いちゃって かたち縫いが風に
dreaming away, shaping the stitches into the wind.
ヂニナスベテ解き明かす 心満たすよ
Unraveling everything, filling my heart.
忍びてこなす知識を 刺激して素敵に
Skillfully handling knowledge, stimulating and wonderfully
生きてる身体も素敵さ アッパッパ
living life in a wonderful body, uppappa!
我が道を行く 今日こそ
Walking my own path, today's the day!
Shine 眩しすぎる 陽射しに目がくらみそうさ
Shine, the dazzling sunlight almost blinds me,
このまま 果てしない 太陽に灼かれて消えてしまいそうさ
as if I'll burn away under the endless sun.
重力反比例 真っ逆様に空へと
Anti-gravity, heading straight up into the sky.
Dive Over 越えて行け 目の前に立ちふさがるもの
Dive Over, go beyond what stands in your way,
すべて飛び越えて次のStageへ 一歩踏み出して
leaping over everything to take a step to the next stage.
昨日までの日々にさようなら 振り返りはしない 今はただ前へ
Saying goodbye to yesterday, no looking back, now moving straight ahead.
Cry 辛くても 沈みゆく夕日に涙を隠して
Cry, even through the pain, hiding tears in the setting sun,
月がほら 暗闇でも道を照らしてくれている
look, the moon is lighting the path even in the dark.
無重力状態 いつか辿り着ける
Weightless state, we'll reach it someday.
I can Over 超えて行け 自身の限界はまだ先にあるんだ
I can Over, push past, my limits are still ahead.
次のLevelへ 百歩進んだら それだけの足跡が残る
Moving to the next level, every hundred steps leave their footprints.
立ち止まることなく ひたむきに前へ
Without stopping, earnestly moving forward.
約束の地まで 掲げよう バッテン バッテン 点々 点々
Raise it up to the promised land, cross cross dot dot...
死んだら 美味しいの愛を あけましょわ
If you die, let's open up delicious love!
我らの絆は しみしみで 一人残らず鍋が完成
Our bonds are steeped deep, leaving no one behind as the nabe is complete!
笑顔で食べれば 心が一つとなる 誇るべき仲間です
Eating with a smile brings our hearts together as a proud family!
SHAKE★NABE ハッピーラッキーソリディティー ひとりじゃ征服できない
SHAKE★NABE, happy lucky solidarity, you can't conquer it alone!
ワクワクのスマイルを広げて この味を超えたいんだ
Spreading an excited smile, I want to surpass this taste!
SHAKE★NABE ワッチャワッチャ ごちゃまぜで 不調和ったり
SHAKE★NABE, chaotic and mixed up, harmonizing discordantly,
みんなでジョインジョイン あちらこちらで ポンッと折れた
joining together everywhere, snapping with a pop!
世界制服 二人じゃない 正解の君にポーズ
Conquering the world, not just two of us, striking a pose for you in the right answer!
さあ どこへ向うのも 頑なで声をとがらせ
Now, wherever we head, stubbornly raising our voices,
喧嘩だからに 絶望の海を越えるため
in a quarrel, to cross the sea of despair.
つまり本気 孤独が痛い 素敵なメイクのスパピュアパーティーラビーに
In short, it's serious, loneliness hurts, at a wonderful make-up spa-pure party for rabii!
スーパーフュージョン ジャパニーズ パーティーラビーに
Super fusion Japanese party rabii!
心を解き放て
Set your heart free,
ほらどうぞどうぞ 身を任せて
come on, go ahead, surrender yourself.
もう逃げられない ほら
You can't run away anymore, look,
闇に染まれば
if you are dyed in darkness...
世界を塗り替えろ 望みはくれてやろう 全て常識 打ち捨てろ
Repaint the world, I'll grant your wishes, discard all common sense!
狂い狂い狂い倒せ 火をつけろ
Go crazy, wild, and overthrow everything, light the fire!
全てを喰らいつくせ
Devour everything completely,
秘密を教えてやろう
I'll teach you the secret!
常夜リペイント
Everlasting Night Repaint!
右も左も まだ僕らは分からずに
Right or left, we still don't know,
ただゴールだけ 決めてしまえって
Let's just decide on a goal and go,
姿も形も 色も違うけど
Though our forms, shapes, and colors differ,
同じ歩幅で 隣を歩ける
We can walk side by side at the same pace.
今日はどう過ごそう メンバー
How shall we spend today, members?
妄想でさえ語り合おうよ 明日も
Let's talk about even our wildest daydreams, tomorrow too.
天気予報で気分が変わっても
Even if the weather forecast changes our mood,
雨のち晴れなら 一休みしてから
If it goes from rain to shine, let's take a break first
扉を開けよう
And open the door.
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ場所できっと出会う
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely meet in the same place,
上手くいかない日も 愛しく思えたんだ
Even days that didn't go well felt precious.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら 真剣に向き合ってさ
No matter how silly the plan, facing each other seriously,
誰よりも信じてた 必死に生きてきたんだ
Believing more than anyone, we lived for all we're worth,
いつだって笑えるように
So we can always smile.
前も後ろも まだ僕らは分からずに
Front or back, we still don't know,
ただゴールだけ 目印にして
Let's just make the goal our landmark
旗を掲げた
And raise our flag.
今日はどう過ごそう メンバー
How shall we spend today, members?
煩悩でさえ預け合おうよ この先に
Let's entrust even our worldly desires to each other, ahead,
何が待ってたとしても変わらない 一つずつ積み上げたこの欠片を
No matter what awaits, these fragments we piled up one by one
後悔しないだろう
Won't be regretted.
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ想いをきっと描く
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely envision the same feelings,
どこか足りないピースも それで良かったんだ
Even missing pieces were fine just as they were.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら 真剣に向き合ってさ
No matter how silly the plan, facing each other seriously,
日が暮れては帰ろうねと
Wishing that as the sun sets, we'd head home together.
当たり前のこんな日々が
These ordinary days like this
どんな輝く宝石よりも
Are more precious than any shining jewel.
互いにふざけ合った日だって
Even days when we teased each other,
抱き合った日だって 傷つけ合った日だって
Days we hugged, days we hurt each other,
全部全部が鮮やかに浮かんでいくよ いつかの遠い遠い空へと
All of it vividly floats up, toward a distant, distant sky.
遠い空へ
Toward a distant sky.
ねえ僕らどうしたって同じ場所できっと出会う
Hey, no matter what, we'll surely meet in the same place,
どうしたってここが居場所だって分かる
No matter what, I know this is where I belong,
混ざり合った声も 心地よかったんだ
And our blended voices felt so comforting.
どんな下らない作戦だって 顔を合わせながら 真剣に向き合ってさ
No matter how silly the plan, facing each other seriously,
誰よりも信じてた 必死に生きてきたんだ
Believing more than anyone, we lived for all we're worth,
いつだって笑えるように
So we can always smile,
明日も笑えるように
So we can smile tomorrow too.
holoXの皆様、いつもholoXを応援していただき本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for always supporting holoX.
約3年前、緊張していた我々をあたたかく迎えていただいた時から今日まで、皆様からのたくさんの勇気とエネルギーをいただいてきました。
Ever since you warmly welcomed us when we were nervous 3 years ago, up until today, we've received so much courage and energy from everyone.
皆殿に
To you all,
少しでも元気をお届けできたでしょうか、
I wonder if we were able to bring you even a little bit of energy.
少しでも皆殿が元気になっていてくれてたらとても嬉しいです。
If it made you all even a little more energetic, I'd be so happy.
今日5人でホロックス3周年記念ライブは最後だけれどちゃんとやり遂げられて本当に良かったです。
Today's Holox 3rd anniversary live with the five of us was only at the end, but we managed to pull it off properly and I'm really glad.
皆さん声が戻るまで待っていてくださり本当にありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for waiting until my voice came back.
3周年をこの5人とホロックスの皆さんと一緒に迎えられて本当に良かったです。
I'm so glad we could celebrate our 3rd anniversary together with these five and all of you Holox members.
そしてホロックスの皆へ、デビューから今日までずっと一緒にいてくれて、頑張ってくれて本当にありがとうございます。
And to everyone in Holox, thank you so much for being with me and working hard from our debut until today.
今回風邪のことでライブが元気になっちゃった時も心強く承諾してくれて励ましてくれて、本当に感謝しかないです。
Even when the live got energetic because of a cold this time, you strongly accepted it and encouraged me, and I can't thank you enough.
ラプラスへ、何びっくりしてんの？一緒にバカやってたくさん笑わせてくれて本当にありがとう。
To Laplus, what are you surprised about? Thank you so much for acting foolish with me and making me laugh a lot.
時刻があるかわかりませんが、そのおかげさんと優しさにとても救われています。
I don't know if there's time, but thanks to that and your kindness, I've been saved so much.
ルイねえ、いつもたくさん話を聞いてくれてありがとう。声が出ない時ずっと連絡してくれてありがとう。いつも自信がない風も自信つけてくれて本当にありがとう。
Lui-nee, thank you always for listening to me so much. Thank you for keeping in touch the whole time my voice wouldn't come out. Thank you so much for giving confidence to someone who always lacks it.
こよちゃんへ、いつも頑張る元気をくれて本当にありがとう。いつも一生懸命な姿を見てエネルギーたくさんもらっています。声が出なくて不安な時も声かけてくれてありがとう。
Koyo-chan, thank you so much for always giving me the energy to try hard. Seeing your hard-working figure gives me so much energy. Thank you for speaking to me even when I was worried about losing my voice.
黒へ、ちょっとしたことも気にかけてくれて、声をかけてくれて本当にありがとう。さりげない優しさにたくさん救われました。
Chloe, thank you so much for caring about the little things and reaching out to me. I was saved so much by your casual kindness.
本当は卒業すごく寂しいけれど、寂しいよ！バカヤロー！だよ。
Honestly, graduation is super lonely, but it's lonely! You idiot!
ずっとこれからの暗いの未来も応援しています。
I will continue to support your dark future ahead as well.
困った時は頼ってくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you rely on me when you're in trouble.
そして最後にこの5人がホロックスで本当に良かったです。みんなのことがずっと大好きです。本当にありがとうございます。風真いろはより。
And lastly, I'm so glad these five are in Holox. I'll always love everyone. Thank you very much. From Kazama Iroha.
よく読めました。
I read it well.
えーまずはホロックス3周年ありがとうございます。
Um, first of all, thank you very much for Holox's 3rd anniversary.
そこまでの都合で5人揃ってのライブは最後になってしまうんですが
Due to circumstances, this will be the last live with all five of us together, but...
ホロックスの皆さんがたくさんの応援と愛を届けてくれたので最高のライブになったと思っています。本当にありがとうございます。
Everyone in Holox has sent us so much support and love, so I think it became the best live. Thank you so much.
最高のライブになったと思っています。本当にありがとうございました。
I think it became the ultimate live. Thank you very much.
賑やかでカオスで自由だけど、ここぞという時に一丸できるホロックスとの絆思い出は大切にして歩んでいきたいと思います。
Lively, chaotic, and free, but I want to cherish the bonds and memories with Holox, who can unite when it counts, and walk forward.
ホロックスの皆も、ありがとうございました！
Thank you to everyone in HoloX too!
こちらこそ。
Our pleasure.
泣かない雰囲気だしてさ、
Trying not to make it emotional...
泣いてたじゃん！
You were crying!
だって坂道元が泣いたらと思って...
Because I thought if Sakamata cried...
泣いてただろ！泣いちゃったよ！
You were crying! I ended up crying!
ホロックスの皆さんへ、
To everyone in HoloX,
まずは3年間応援してくれて、本当にありがとう！
thank you so much for supporting us for three years!
秘密結社が乗り込んできた異質な形だったので受け入れてもらえるかドキドキしていました。
It was an unusual way for us to join already in progress, so I was so nervous about whether we'd be accepted.
温かく迎え入れてくれた皆さんのおかげで、5人揃って3年間活動できました。
Thanks to everyone who warmly welcomed us, we were able to stay active together as five for three years.
こうして5人団結できたのは、みんなが愛してくれたからです。
The reason we were able to stay united as five is because you all loved us.
本当に支えられてきたなって心底から思っています。
I sincerely feel that we have been immensely supported.
周年は最後になるけど絆はなくならないからね。
This will be our last anniversary, but our bond will never disappear.
これからも変わらぬ応援よろしくお願いします！
Please continue to support us just the same!
忙しい中クッキーを持ってきてくれたり本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for bringing cookies even when busy!
心的に大変な時期だろうけど気にせず気軽に話してね。
I know it's a tough time mentally, but don't worry and feel free to talk.
別々の道を歩くけど友達でホロックスなのは変わらないよ！
We'll walk different paths, but we'll always remain friends and HoloX!
いつも歌みたを褒めてくれたり教えてくれてありがとう！
Thank you for always praising my cover songs and teaching me!
ダンスを練習してくれていて本当に最高で嬉しいです。
It's the absolute best and makes me so happy that you practice the dances.
最近は本気なんだなって感じられるくらい好きでいてくれてありがとう。
Thank you for loving it so much that I can tell you're serious lately.
自己肯定感が低い私にとってすごく助かっています。
It's helped me so much since I have low self-esteem.
この5人で本当に良かった。これからも仲良くしてね！
HoloX is truly wonderful with these five. Please keep getting along!
リハで話して新しい夢ができました。ホロックスライブがしたい！
Talking in rehearsals gave me a new dream. I want to do a HoloX live!
黒たんを引っ張りだします！
I'll drag Kurotan out!
可愛い　可愛いでしょう？
Kawaii... Kawaii, right?
ラプラス員聖。
Laplus-sensei.
ほんとだ、可愛い。
So cute.
まずは、ホロックスのみんなへ。
First of all, to all the holoX members,
えー、今日私たちのためにこの配信を見てくださり本当にありがとうございます。
thank you so much for watching this stream for us today.
ホロックスのみんながいるから私たちはこうやって3周年を迎えることができました。
Because all of holoX is here, we're able to celebrate our 3rd anniversary like this.
3年の間ホロックスでも個人個人の活動でも色々なことがありました。
Over these past 3 years, whether in holoX or in our individual activities,
1周年の時はまだ不安定で心配もかけましたね。
things were still unstable and we had our worries at the 1st anniversary.
私たち自身もこれからどう進むのか未来が霞んでいたとき道を照らしてくれたのはホロックスのみんななんだと思います。
When our future seemed hazy and we wondered how we ourselves would progress, I think it was all of holoX that illuminated our path.
ホロックスにとってホロックスは太陽的な存在だと思っています。
To holoX, holoX is a solar-like existence.
これから鷹嶺はホロライブでの活動は終了しちゃってホロックスは4人で活動していきますが
From here on, Sakamata's activities on HoloLive will end, and holoX will continue as four members,
ホロックスはこれからも5人そしてプラスホロックスで永久不滅だと思っております。
but we believe that holoX will forever remain as five, plus holoX.
手が震えてる。
My hands are shaking.
手が震えとる。
They're shaking.
4年目の新たなステージに向かって頑張っていくので、これからも見守ってくれると嬉しいです。
I'll do my best heading toward the 4th year's new stage, so I'd be happy if you continue to watch over us.
これからもよろしくお願いします。そして、ホロックスのみんな。
Thank you for everything, and to all of holoX.
まずはラプ。
First is Lap.
自由奔放で勘違いされがちな総帥ですが、誰よりもホロックスを愛しメンバーを愛しているのは私達ホロックスに伝わってます。
Though her wild and reckless nature often leads to misunderstandings, her immense love for holoX and the members is something that is truly conveyed to us.
ラプが総帥しかありえないなと思ってます。
Lap being our general is something that couldn't possibly be any other way.
自信を持ってこれからも私たちを導いてください。
Please continue to guide us with confidence.
自信を持ってください。
Please have confidence.
あなたは総帥です。
You're our general!
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you so much.
そしてこよ。
And Koyo.
最初からこよはやる気満々まんで私たちを引っ張ってくれて、私もすごく心の支えにしてました。あ、今もです。
Right from the start, Koyo's overflowing enthusiasm pulled us along, and she was a huge emotional support for me—ah, she still is.
今もしてます。
She still is!
2人でデビュー直後不安なことを語り歩道を歩いたの覚えてますか？
Do you remember walking the path of anxiety right after our debut, just the two of us?
歩いた。
I walked.
歩いたね。
We walked, didn't we?
その時の相談事とかこよあったと思うんですけど、今はみんなに愛される素敵なアイドルそして配信者になってるから、これからも先陣を切って色んな道を切り拓いていってください。いつでも頼ってね。
We had various discussions back then, but now that you're a wonderful idol and broadcaster loved by everyone, please continue to forge ahead and pioneer new paths, and you can always rely on me.
うん。
Yes.
いろは。
Iroha.
はい。
Yes.
言いたいことなかなか言い出せない癖がまだ抜けてなくて心配になりますけど今まで通り手を携えてたまに道に迷いながらお互いマイペースに活動を楽しんでいきましょう。
She still has trouble voicing the things she wants to say, which always makes me worry, but just like before, let's hold hands and occasionally wander off on detours as we enjoy our activities at our own respective paces.
またかまぼこ食べに行こうね。
Let's go eat kamaboko again!
食べる！
I'll eat!
食べよう！
Let's eat!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
そして、クロヱ。
And Chloe.
えー、もうクロヱには言いたいことを個別に言ったのでわざわざというか感じではないんですけど。
Well, I actually had things I wanted to say to Chloe individually, so I went out of my way to—well, not that there's much.
また、またですね。
Not much, huh?
まあ、あの、お泊まりをしたこともあったし、喧嘩をしたこともあったし、色々あったけどデビュー前から最初に仲良くなったメンバーがクロヱでよかったなって思います。
Well, we went on dates together, we fought too, we had all kinds of things happen, but ever since before our debut, I've always felt so glad that Chloe was the one I became close with first.
それはこれからも変わらないです。これからのホロックスを楽しみながら見ててくだいさい。
That's something that will never change, so please keep enjoying holoX from here on out.
絶対引きずり出すから。
I'll definitely drag you along!
いや、それ怖いよ！
Hey, that's terrifying!
クロヱの健康を願ってます。ゆっくり休め、クロヱ。
I'm praying for Chloe's health. Please get plenty of rest, Chloe.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
本当にありがとうございます。
Really, thank you.
えー、4年目も頼り甲斐のない、ええと、頼り甲斐のないアホな女幹部ですけど
I'm just a foolish woman leader with zero dependability for this 4th year as well,
これからもよろしくお願いします。楽しくしていきましょう。いつもありがとう、ルイ。
but let's continue to happily enjoy things together from here on out as well. Thank you always, Lui.
じゃあ最後に総帥。
And finally, Laplus.
お願いします。
Thank you.
なんで最後なんだろうって
Why is it me last?
総帥だからだよ！なぜなら総帥だからだよ！
Because you're the general, duh!
ちょっとおたっちは恥ずかしいのでみんなの方を向いて読めません。
Since this is a bit embarrassing, I can't look at everyone's faces.
えっとな、Holoxの皆様
Um, everyone in HoloX,
いつも活動を応援してくれてありがとう。
thank you always for supporting our activities.
活動している時、いつも一緒にいられたわけでは全くなかったですけど、
Even though we couldn't always be together while active,
5人で集まった時の実感がというか、
that sense of reality when the five of us get together...
台本が全く進まないほど喋り続けるこの5人が大好き！
I love these five who keep talking so much
that the script doesn't progress at all!
謝りたいこと、感謝したいこと、感謝されたこと本当にいっぱいあります。
There are truly so many things I want to apologize for,
thank, and be thanked for.
なんか、テスト変わったな。ルイ。本当に、本当に我が輩たちは喋りすぎです。
Wait, the test changed, huh? Lui.
Truly, truly, we talk way too much.
楽しい時間をいつもありがとう。
Thank you always for the fun times.
はい。ありがとうございます。
Yeah. Thank you.
で、ルイからは人間界のいろんなことを教わりました。
And from Lui, I learned all sorts of things about the human world.
我が輩は元から大人ですが、もっと人間として大人になれた気がします。
I was an adult to begin with, but I feel like
I've become even more of an adult as a human.
育ててくれてありがとう。
Thank you for raising me.
親？ママじゃん。よろしくね、ラプちん。
A parent? She's a mama.
Nice to meet you, Lap-chin.
そしてこよりさん、最近本当に気持ち悪がられている気がして、
And Koyori-san, lately I feel like
people find me really creepy,
いやそんなことないよ！興奮しています。
No, that's not true! I'm just excited.
ならよかった。
That's good then.
こよりとはとても正反対だと思います。努力家で正直で真っすぐなこより。
I think Koyori is the exact opposite.
Hardworking, honest, and straightforward Koyori.
頑張ること、正直になること、正面突破が大嫌いな我が輩。だからこそ、こよりのことを本気で尊敬しています。
Working hard, being honest, and tackling things head-on
are things I hate. That's why I truly respect Koyori.
早く結婚しようね。
Let's get married soon.
アンサー言われてたんだ。
She was told the answer.
言われた後なんだ。いろは馬鹿ガキ。
After being told. Iroha is a stupid brat.
我が輩も我が輩にはないものをたくさん持っています。こいつは本当に一生懸命です。
I also have many things I don't have.
This one works really hard.
頑張ることをやめません。でもたまに空回っているようで、いろは我が輩が助けてやるからってなっちまいます。
She never stops trying. But sometimes she spins her wheels,
and ends up saying, "Iroha, I'll help you out."
悪友、ライバル、家族、全部まとめたかまりみたいないろはです。これからもたくさん殴らせてください。
Frenemy, rival, family, Iroha is like a bundle of all those.
Please let me beat you up a lot more.
いいよ、殴り返すけどね！無理です。
Sure, I'll hit you back though! No way.
ひざまずけよ！
Kneel down!
そして黒え、おつとめご苦労様でした。
And Kuroe, thank you for your hard work on your duties.
え、キープしょ！待って待って待って。
Eh, keep it! Wait, wait, wait.
娑婆娑婆、出所しょ娑婆なんだ。
Out of prison, she's in freedom.
黒えはさ、この前LINEでラプラスって本当優しいよねって送ってきたけど、あれはどういうことなんだか。
Kuroe sent me a message on LINE the other day saying,
"Laplus, you're really kind," but what did she mean by that?
本当にやめて！本当に本当にやめて、それは！
Seriously stop! Seriously, seriously stop that!
我が輩は、黒えに優しくした思い出がなくて、
I don't have any memories of being kind to Kuroe,
いやもういいよ！
oh, that's enough!
忘れてくれよじゃあ。あと、黒えさんは、
Forget it then. Also, Kuroe-san,
我が輩の歌が好きすぎるんじゃいでしょうか。
don't you like my singing way too much?
好き！いいよね。
Love it! It's great, right?
好き。黒えのチャンネルから我が輩との歌ってみたが2本も上がって、我が輩とだけです。本当いいでしょうか。
Love it. Two covers with me came out on Kuroe's channel,
and it's only with me. Is that really okay?
これは好きだなと思っています。
I think I like this.
最後に本音が聞きたいです。
Lastly, I want to hear your true feelings.
たくさん聞きたいこともあるし、たくさん言いたいこともあるし、本当はもっと一緒に歌いたかったし、
There's a lot I want to ask, a lot I want to say,
and honestly I wanted to sing together more,
黒えもそうだよね。
Kuroe, you feel the same, right?
黒え、辞めるなんて全然思ってなくて、
Kuroe, I never thought about quitting at all.
今まではずっと自分勝手にやってて、改めてホロックスって大切だなと思いました。
Until now I've just done whatever I wanted,
and I realized anew how precious HoloX is.
にわさらめちゃくちゃやりたいこととか、思い浮かじゃって、我が輩めっちゃバカじゃん！
Randomly things I want to do popped into my head,
and I'm such an idiot!
でも黒えやめないでとか、めっちゃわがままなバカじゃん！だからせめてただのめっちゃバカになるために、黒えが活動を辞めるのをがまんすることにしました。
But being a selfish idiot saying "Kuroe, don't quit!"...
So at least, to just be a huge idiot, I decided to make Kuroe stop quitting her activities.
でも全然辞めるとか嫌で、本当のこと言ってごめんなさい。
But the idea of quitting at all sucks,
I'm sorry for telling the truth.
でも、活動を辞めても別に黒えバイバイなわけじゃないから、
But even if she stops activities,
it's not like Kuroe is saying bye-bye forever,
自分は生きるめておとなしくめっちゃ笑顔でホロックスで今まで一番のライブを作って送り出すことに成功だよ！
I successfully managed to send her off by being well-behaved,
smiling huge, and making the best HoloX live ever!
黒え、いってらっしゃい。ごめんね、ありがとう。
Kuroe, have a safe trip. Sorry, thank you.
大好き、またね。そして最後にホロックスへ、今までありがとう。これからもよろしく。以上！
Love you, see you again. And lastly to HoloX,
thank you for everything until now. Best regards going forward. That's all!
体骨で。
With my tailbone.
3年間ありがとうございました。
Thank you for these 3 years.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
じゃあ最後はエンディングです。今日は来てくれて
Well then, lastly is the ending. Thank you for coming today.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
Can you feel my soul
Baby, up & up now
Nothing bad happened.
楽しんだってまわる宿命 義...
Even if we fret, the rotating karma...
"アイドルなんが"という言葉を
A phrase like "idol"...
見てもしないくせに
Even though you don't even watch,
頑張りを当然
Trying your best is only natural.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force images on us.
"アイドルなんが"
"Idols"...
という言葉は 一番
Are number one!
さあ Com'on 覚悟決め定
Come on, deal with the devil.
アップダウンは世の常
Ups and downs are the way of the world.
躓いたって動かない
Even if I stumble, I won't back down.
まだベイビーね
Still a baby, aren't you?
散われをかな
Scattered, weren't they?
ほら もういいかい
Hey, ready or not?
その内僕が
Before long, I...
僕じゃなくなって
Stopped being me.
もう一体
Hey, where am I?
すべてを喰らいつくせ
I'll devour everything.
(ラッパッパーラッパッ)
(Rappa-pa, rappa-pa)
教えてやろう
I'll teach you...
僕らは真面仲間です (ハイ!)
We are true comrades (Yes!)
ハッピーラッキー×ソリダリティ
Happy Lucky x Solidarity
ひとりじゃ征服させない!
You can't get away alone!
みんな！
Everyone!
みんな！みんな！みんな！みんな！
Everyone, look!
カメラ持ってきた！
I brought the camera!
カメラほら！
Look at the camera!
お、カメラ？
Oh, a camera?
写真撮るよ、チーズ！
Let's take a picture. Say cheese!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
写真でござんな？
Oh, it's a photo!
じゃあみんな！写真撮るよ！
Hey everyone, let's take a picture!
ほい、おー！きてきてきてきて！
Okay! Come, come, come!
じゃあみんな最高の笑顔で！
Alright, everyone show your best smile!
はい！
Yeah!
ハーイ！じゃあ、３、２、１、holoXー！
holoX!